( WIND HOWLS )
( MYSTERIOUS MUSIC )
GIRL : My story can never be told .
I write it over and over
wherever we find shelter .
I write of what I cannot speak .
The truth .
I write all I know of it .
And then I throw the pages to the wind .
Maybe the birds can read it .
( WISTFUL MUSIC )
( INDISTINCT CHATTER )
This yours ?
I often find them here , these scraps .
Must float down from someone 's window .
( READS ) " She had meant to smother the baby
" as soon as it was born .
" But something made her look at it .
" She heard the thundering heartbeat .
" She smelt the baby 's bloodied head .
" And love confounded her . "
It 's just a scrap , like you say .
But there 's a story there .
You can feel it .
Shall we walk a little ?
My story starts with Clara .
One day , it will end with her .
Clara ,
full of secrets .
My saviour .
My burden .
My muse .
( SULTRY ROCK SONG PLAYS )
- Hey ! - ( GRUNTS AND SCREAMS )
- Fuckin ' hell . Wendy . - I 'll call you back .
- FUCK you ! - ( GROWLS )
( MAN SCREAMS )
- ( GRUNTS ) - ( GROANS )
You bastard ! Did you see that ?
He fucking attacked me .
- What 's she done ? - Really fucked his nose .
- Yeah , well , he deserved it . - ( CONTINUES GROANING )
Ernie . Get him out of here , mate .
My nose ! My nose .
OLD MAN : Would you care for tea ?
Please come in .
I have been working here for 14 nights . I want my pay !
You 're not on the books . What pay ?
( ROCK SONG CONTINUES )
( PEOPLE CHATTER )
Excuse me . Have you seen this girl ?
WOMAN : No . Sorry , mate .
Sorry .
No .
- Oi ! What are you doing ? - Sorry , babe , but they owe me .
- No ! You can 't take till money ! - They owe me .
- Hello , Clara . - ( GASPS )
- ( GRUNTS ) - Arrgh !
We get a lot of bitches in here ,
but she took the fucking prize .
Shame - she was morbidly sew .
- ( PANTS ) - Ahh !
( PANTS )
( GRUNTS ) Move !
( GRUNTS )
( WOMAN SCREAMS )
Ahh !
( GRUNTS )
Clara !
( PANTS )
Shit ! Fuck !
( GRUNTS )
( SCREAMING )
( BOTH GRUNT )
The tedium I have experienced in this pursuit .
- My time you have wasted . - Ahh !
You would sell nations with your whoredoms .
Come on . You know who I 'm looking for .
- Where is she ? - Ahh !
Huh ? Where is she ? !
I was him once .
And that girl ...
Love confounded me for her .
I loved her my whole life through .
Your wife ?
She was married to my brother John .
Most happily -
She never knew the way I felt .
Nor did he .
There comes a time in life when secrets should be told .
You 've got secrets , haven 't you ?
There was a story told when I was a boy
about the neamh mairbh -
the revenants .
Neither dead nor alive .
The priests used to tell it to frighten us .
My name is Eleanor Webb .
Eleanor Webb
I am ready .
- Are you sure ? - ( CHUCKLES )
I 've spent quite enough time here ,
believe me .
( GRUNTS )
I feel a great peace .
As if order is about to be restored .
She is an aberration .
I don 't know what that means , sir .
Where do you think you 're going ?
I was going to clean the wound , sir .
You 've been cut . It 's conspicuous .
( WATER RUNS )
All the time you 've had and you 've learnt nothing .
Truly , you 're base .
Close your eyes .
( PANTS )
( DOOR CLOSES )
- Clara ? - Get out .
How could you bring someone here ?
- He was stronger than I thought . - This is our home !
Eleanor , we have to leave .
- I 'm not moving on again . - I had to do it !
- One day , you 'll understand . - What , when I 'm old enough ?
You have no idea - no fucking idea - of what I do for you .
- You did that for ME ? ! - Pack !
- I liked it here . - I said pack !
- Who was he ? - No-one .
( DOG BARKS )
- ( WOMAN LAUGHS ) - ( INDISTINCT CHATTER )
( SINGS ) ♪ Mother was bathing her baby one night
♪ Youngest of 10 and a poor little mite
♪ Mother was fat and the baby was thin
♪ It was naught but a
( JOINS IN ) ♪ Skellington wrapped up in skin
♪ Mother turned round for the soap from the rack ... ♪
- Thank you . - MAN : Alright , see you , girls .
MAN : Shall we have a look in the greenhouse , then ?
MAN 2 : Alright , then .
( SHEEP BLEAT )
( CHOIR SINGS ' COVENTRY CAROL ' )
( SEAGULLS SQUAWK )
( ELEANOR PANTS )
We 've been here before .
CLARA : Don 't be silly . Come on .
But don 't you remember ?
( BUSY AMUSEMENT ARCADE NOISE )
It 's gonna be good for us here , I can feel it .
You said that about the last place .
( SCOFFS ) What , that dump that we just left ?
I 've forgotten it already .
What 's the matter ?
You can 't throw the past away as if it didn 't happen .
My concern is now , OK ?
( SIGHS ) Silly sod .
Why don 't you go and play on the amusements , yeah ?
Gonna make us some money .
MAN : Go on .
ELEANOR : Clara is never alone .
She finds money and company every day .
It comes easily to her .
Like lying .
- Who 's that ? You know her ? - No ...
- Have you seen her ? - No .
ELEANOR : But I like solitude .
I walk .
And the past walks with me .
It lives .
( LAUGHTER AND CHATTER )
( PLAYS BEETHOVEN 'S ' SONATA IN c , Op. 2 , No. 3 - ADAGIO ' )
( PIANO PLAYING CONTINUES )
( CLARA SNIFFS )
( SNIFFS )
Hi .
It 's 50 for a blow , 100 for full whack .
( CONTINUES PLAYING SONATA )
( FINISHES PLAYING )
Did they hire you ?
You 're busking .
You can pass a hat around .
I don 't mind .
That was great .
Can you speak ?
I haven 't got a hat .
( CHUCKLES )
How do you remember all those notes ?
I remember everything .
It 's a burden .
So
you know anything else ?
Try and liven them up .
It 's the valley of the stiffs in here .
I have to go .
I finish at 10 : 00 .
( FLICKS SWITCHES )
Come in .
50 . Lovely .
So , are you on holiday , then ?
- No . - Oh , you live round here ?
Yeah .
- You fancied a bit of company . - She ...
( CRIES )
Who ?
Mum .
She died .
Oh , I 'm so sorry .
There was a funeral .
I couldn 't .
( SNIFFS ) Yeah , I ran away from it .
I 've not been out ... I 've not been out since .
( CRIES )
But your grief , that shows how much you loved her .
And love is a very good thing .
I bet she 'd be proud of you .
A lovely son like you .
No , I never made her proud .
I just ...
I don 't even answer the phone .
You know ?
I messed up the business , I can 't pay her debts .
Found 50 quid in one of her old books ,
and what do I spend it on ?
- ( SOBS ) - Ohh .
Human contact .
( SIGHS )
- Are you OK ? - Yeah .
- Yeah ? - I 'm sorry , love .
I 'm Camilla .
Noel .
So , what sort of a business did your mum have , then , Noel ?
( SNIFFS )
It was a guesthouse . I trashed it .
Was it a big place ?
Yeah , it 's fairly big .
Well ...
Do you ...
Shall we go back to your place , then ?
- Yeah ? - Yeah .
- Be nice . - Yeah ...
- You could come back to mine . - Yeah .
( WAVES CRASH )
Glad you waited for me .
I didn 't .
How did you learn to play like that ?
I practised .
For how long ?
200 years .
That 's how it feels anyways , doesn 't it ?
Passed around a teacup .
Raised some cash for you .
It 's not much .
Thank you .
And that piece of paper .
That 's my phone number .
I don 't have a phone .
( come JINGLE )
So
ni ... nice
nice to meet you .
Goodbye .
CLARA : Ella ! Ella !
Look what I found ! ( GIGGLES )
We 're damsels in distress .
NOEL : Oh .
Do you know what Noel is , Ella ?
He 's a knight in shining armour .
Come to deliver us from evil , aren 't you ? ( CHUCKLES )
This is my little baby sister .
- Hi . - Hello .
There we go .
( SIGHS )
Been looking for you everywhere .
- NOEL : Can 't find my keys . - CLARA : Ohh .
I 'll just open up .
Come on , then .
Look , I 'm trusting you , Camilla .
( CLARA GIGGLES )
- Don 't . - I won 't .
Look , I 'm not saying it 's tidy .
It was a hotel once . ( CHUCKLES )
- ( CLARA CHUCKLES ) - Then a boarding house .
My mum had the top two floors .
Used to do B Bs , you know ? Families and that .
But then it was more , you know , the welfare lot .
It 's a bit run-down now , but she wouldn 't let it go .
Loved the views , you see .
Fantastic view of the pier from up here .
CLARA : Lovely .
This is the dining area .
Well ...
It 's nice .
Yeah , it 's lovely .
NOEL : It 's a bit of a state , like I said , but ...
I wasn 't expecting company . ( CHUCKLES )
( GIGGLES )
Tell my sister where her room is first .
Yeah .
Ella
I 'll show you to your room .
( CLARA HUMS )
- I went round the house and ... - ( CLARA SINGS GENTLE SONG )
... smashed things up .
I didn 't want to look at myself .
Camilla said that , um
you lost your mum too .
She 's your legal guardian ?
That 's brave of her .
Well , I understand what she 's had to do .
Do you ?
Well , she needs money .
What I 'm saying is , um
I don 't care .
- You can stay . - Thank you .
( WISTFUL PIANO MUSIC )
CLARA : Only those prepared to die will find eternal life .
( SQUEAKING )
Go on . Go on .
This is the end .
- Of what ? - Of time .
( SEAGULLS SQUAWK )
( WATER SPLASHES )
( CLARA SIGHS AND GROANS )
CLARA : Good boy .
( GRUNTS AND GROANS )
( OMINOUS MUSIC )
( SIRENS WAIL )
( CAMERA CLICKS )
Who was he ?
It 's in the past , Ella . Let it go .
- Who was he ? - He was a fucking monster .
I should get a medal for what I did to him .
Will we move on today ?
Are you tired , my love ?
Well ...
I reckon that we should
hang on here for a few days , don 't you ?
Yeah . We can lay low , get some rest .
Get some money .
I could start up one of my old businesses like in the old days .
- You don 't have to do that . - Oh , come on , Ella .
Look at this place - it 's perfect . We 'd rake it in .
Why don 't we find another way ?
- It 's alright , angel . - ( GRUNTS )
CLARA : I 'll make sure you 're not involved .
- ( GROWLS ) - ( YELLS )
- ( LAUGHS ) - ( GRUNTS AND PANTS )
I 'm sorry , Noel . Ohh ...
( GIGGLES )
I was worried I dreamt you .
I thought I 'd wake up and you 'd be gone .
Why would I leave ?
You 've got everything I need .
- ( WAVES CRASH ) - ( RAINDROPS PATTER )
Eleanor Webb .
Look at you .
Fair as a lily .
I know your mother .
My mother is dead .
Is that what they told you ?
They 've fed you on lies .
Your mother ...
Your mother stole something from me .
Now I 'll steal something from her .
( PANTS )
- My disease has no cure . - ( WHIMPERS )
And when I 've finished with you ,
you 'll be a child no longer .
Look at me !
NOEL : Eleanor ?
Are you OK ?
Camilla 's told me about how you were in a care home .
She said that ...
She said that bad things happened to you there .
I want you to know that nothing bad will happen
while you 're living here .
I promise . OK ?
Her name 's not Camilla .
- And she 's not my sister . - My name 's Claire .
It 's Clara .
- She was born Clara . - But I prefer Claire .
- Mmm . - Claire .
- Don 't . - You lie about me all the time .
If you tell him , I will kill him .
Don 't you sometimes crave to tell the truth ?
There is a code that we survive by , Eleanor . Keep it .
CLARA : So , in a week , say , how much would your mum make ?
NOEL : Uh , high season ?
About a thousand .
CLARA : We could make that in a night .
You could clear all your debts , Noely .
NOEL : Yeah , but ... I want to save you from that life .
CLARA : Well , it wouldn 't have to be me .
You could get some girls in .
NOEL : But ...
Well , this is my mother 's house .
( CLARA SINGS ) ♪ He 's so fair
♪ None can compare
♪ Oh , but his blood runs ruby ... ♪
( MYSTERIOUS MUSIC )
♪ Come , rosy day
♪ Come quick , I pray
♪ Let dreams of love
♪ Be over . ♪
ELEANOR : Once upon a time , there was nothing here .
There was no hotel ,
no promenade .
Just a beach .
Nets hanging out to dry .
Great warships in the bay .
And children picking cock / es for their bread .
My mother was one of those children .
Barefoot in the sand .
- Can you hear me ? - ( GRUNTS SOFTLY )
My mother lives on human blood
and has done for two centuries .
( MAN SHOUTS )
ELEANOR : But once , she was a girl like you .
She 's never spoken of her family .
They 're in the store of things she must forget .
So her tale begins
with two officers waiting to be called to war .
Are they sweet ?
May I try one ?
ELEANOR : One was Midshipman Darvell .
Mmm .
Here .
A pearl for a pearl .
ELEANOR : And the other , his superior , was Captain Ruthven .
May I offer you a ride ?
DARVELL : She 's only a child , Ruthven .
She knows how to ride , I dare say .
Don 't go with him .
ELEANOR : The pearl stays pure forever
while the oyster 's ﬂesh rots around it .
I have a gift for you .
Captain Ruthven !
- ( PEOPLE CHATTER ) - ( CLASSICAL PIANO MUSIC PLAYS )
Here 's a treasure I found on the beach .
Welcome , my dear .
There 's nothing to be afraid of .
Come on .
Let me show you to the captain 's favourite room .
You 'll find only friends here .
You gave me nothing , sir .
You took .
I 've given you your profession .
Welcome to your adult life .
ELEANOR : How many stories start that way ?
Whore .
ELEANOR : Thousands upon thousands .
I shall return
to see what you have learnt .
Come , now . Why do you cry ?
I have a gentleman here
who will soon have you smiling again .
( BABY CRIES )
No children in this household .
You know the rule .
ELEANOR : Once upon a time , I was born .
It is still a fact that the day you are born
is the day you are most likely to be murdered .
More human souls are killed by mothers ' hands
than by the hands of strangers .
My mother tried to murder me .
But love confounded her .
Her note said , " This is my daughter , Eleanor Webb .
" I wish her to live a clean life .
" I shall pay for her upkeep with gold ,
" which I will leave every month that she lives .
" I wish to spare her a life like my own ,
" which has been despoiled from the start .
" Please tell her I 'm dead . "
( CHOIR SINGS ' COVENTRY CAROL ' )
So I led that clean life .
I sang the orphan 's song .
I learned that virtue and modesty
would be my path to bliss .
North Haven Private Orphanage was my abode .
I wish I could have called it home .
- Damn ! - I 'm sorry !
Fuck .
Oh , that 's gross .
There . There .
( GRUNTS ) Shit , I 've got to get home .
Well , let me get help .
I 've got your bicycle . Don 't worry .
ELEANOR : You need stitches .
BOY : Were you there to enrol ?
- ELEANOR : What ? - ( GRUNTS )
- Have you joined the college ? - I don 't know .
Leave the bike there .
Ohh , I hate blood .
Could you get the doorbell , please ?
( RINGS DOORBELL )
Come on .
- Oh , my God ! What happened ? - He fell .
Oh , my God ! Ohh ... Mark !
Mark ! He 's bleeding !
- Oh , my God ! - ( FOREBODING MUSIC )
- Mark ! - It 's OK . I got him . I got him .
MARK : Get the keys .
Are you his girlfriend ?
( SHOUTS ) Where are the keys ? !
Has he told you ? Ohh !
- MARK : Got the keys ? - WOMAN : Yeah .
WOMAN : Keep it up , keep it up , Frank .
WOMAN : Go , go ! Frank !
( TENSE MUSIC )
( BUSY AMUSEMENT ARCADE NOISE )
( ETTA JAMES ' ' DON 'T CRY BABY' PLAYS OVER PA SYSTEM )
You could do so much better .
- Oi . - Would you like to kiss me ?
What the fuck ? Why ?
In celebration ... of my wickedness .
( BOTH GRUNT )
( MOANS )
Mmm .
The world 'll be more beautiful without you .
It 's alright . I gotcha . It 's OK .
It 's OK .
- I want to die . - No , you don 't .
Not today .
If you still want to die tomorrow , I 'll finish you off myself .
( OMINOUS MUSIC )
( BREATHES TENSELY )
( DOOR OPENS )
Hello ? Oh , hi .
Is it still visiting ?
Thanks for bringing him home .
He hasn 't told me anything about you .
That 's boys for you , isn 't it ?
Have you been going out for long ?
- We just met . - Oh . Oh .
I 'm glad . What 's your name ?
Eleanor .
Gabi .
He takes anticoagulants .
That 's why he bled so much . I expect you 're wondering .
He 's been fighting leukaemia for years .
It 's in remission now , so ... we 're hoping it 's all over .
So full of life .
Please don 't tell him I was here .
( MYSTERIOUS MUSIC )
( BREATHES LABORIOUSLY )
OLD WOMAN : Angel .
ELEANOR : Peace be with you .
May light shine upon you .
OLD WOMAN : You came for me .
Forgive me for what I must do .
- Ohh . Oops ! - ( LAUGHS )
- Oh , hi ! - Hi !
- You speak ? - ( LAUGHS )
Speak English , you schoolgirl thing ?
( BOTH LAUGH )
She better pay like she say or I 'll say no further .
- ( GIGGLES ) - Maybe we do lesbian thing .
- I don 't mind . - ( LAUGHS )
That 's my little baby sister .
She doesn 't drink , she doesn 't join in .
You leave her be . Do you understand ?
Now , your gentlemen are waiting for you .
Now , you be professional , OK ,
otherwise you 're back sucking cocks on the street .
Out !
I 'll try and keep you out of this , OK ?
- In case you shock me ? - We need the money .
I 'm not complaining .
Well , then , wipe that prissy look off your face .
How can I be prissy when I 've seen it all a thousand times before ?
Well , what else are we supposed to do ?
I know I won 't get your thanks
or your gratitude or your respect .
- You could do so much better . - I put money on the table .
- That 's what mothers do . - Mothers care about
the lives their children live .
What kind of life is this ?
( ' BE MY GUEST' BY GAITANA PLAYS )
MAN : Humans need to tell stories .
It 's a fundamental and uniting thing .
It 's through stories that we come to understand ourselves
and we come to understand the world .
So close your eyes .
It 's our own experience that is the starting point
for all our creativity .
Think about your early childhood .
And when I say your name
give me a memory -
a detail , a sensation , a feeling .
The first thing that comes into your mind . OK ?
( GIRL COUGHS )
- MAN : Eleanor . - Mother .
What about her ?
She would come to the skylight at night .
I was afraid .
Why ?
They told me since infancy that she was dead .
And then ?
ELEANOR : The face at the window
had more substance than a ghost .
OK , thanks .
- ELEANOR : And yet ... - Frank .
... I knew it could not live .
Yeah , um ... my friend
David Atkinson .
I 'm the only person who can see him .
Um ...
I was probably too much alone , whatever ,
and David Atkinson used to appear
in my room .
And we 'd play .
And I guess I grew out of him .
He came till I was about seven or eight .
- Yeah . - Thank you .
- OK ... - The really funny thing
is that
years later ,
I found out that the family before us in the house
were called Atkinson .
They lost a baby , like , a cot death .
And the baby 's name
was David .
Uh-huh .
Good story .
So , everyone up .
Now , I want you to think about who you are .
And next time , I would like an essay
entitled
' l Am ' .
And there 's only one rule .
It has to be true .
- ( SEAGULLS SQUAWK ) - You don 't belong here .
This is my mum 's home town .
We came when I got ill .
The health care over here is free , and I was
something of a , um
a drain on our limited resources .
My dad commutes .
I don 't think he likes it much , but
what are you gonna do ?
My mum said you came to see me when I was in hospital .
She , um
she thinks
that ... that you 're my girl .
Would that be so bad ?
- Because I ... - It would be fatal .
Look
I know I 'm ... I 'm ill and all , but ...
No .
For me .
If you lived with a secret
and the secret meant that you must always lie
or be alone ,
and you 'd always lived that way
and yet you longed for change
what would you do ?
I 'd tell the secret .
Tell me .
( PANTS )
ELEANOR : My mother did three things for me .
One , she spared my life the day that I was born .
Two , she paid for my upkeep on her knees and on her back .
And three ,
she gave me the story I can never tell .
( CLARA COUGHS )
By the time I was six ,
she was dying .
Girls like Clara didn 't last .
Her lungs were rotting .
But she clung steadfastly to her brutal life .
( COUGHS )
Where have you been ?
The captain 's been waiting .
ELEANOR : Captain Ruthven had returned from the wars .
Make sure you punish her , sir .
Of all the harlots he had ever made
Clara was his favourite .
You 'll like this one . She fights .
ELEANOR : Then , one winter dawn
a stranger came .
( COUGHS )
( RETCHES )
Are you unwell ?
No , sir .
( STIFLES COUGH )
I remember you .
I 'm much changed , sir .
And what of me ?
Have I changed ?
I have .
More than you could imagine .
Open the curtains .
( GRUNTS )
( GRUNTS ) Oh , curse you , whore . Give me the dark !
Does the light offend you ?
Darvell .
My friend .
( PANTS )
But I was with you .
I saw you dead .
And I thank you for your service .
What do you want ?
I have not come to take from you .
I come to give .
I 'll return at nightfall .
Like you , I prefer the dark .
- No ! - Bitch !
ELEANOR : He answered her questions with blows .
As usual , she endured them .
And she waited for the storm to pass .
( RINGS DOORBELL )
What kind of time do you call this ?
- Linear time . - ( CHUCKLES )
ELEANOR : As the relentless day crept on , the captain told his tale
of events beyond his understanding .
RUTHVEN : There was a rebellion in Ireland .
We were sent to crush it .
Both of us were wounded by the beggarly horde .
My wounds were superficial , but Darvell developed fever .
It decimated him .
I tried to persuade him to come home .
CLARA : That was good of you .
I knew the journey would quicken his decline .
Darvell was rich ,
naive .
He had no heir .
- I had begun to wish him dead . - ( COUGHS )
But before the grave took him , two men entered his life .
Scholars , I presumed , of dead languages
and aged manuscripts .
As if ancient knowledge might keep his death at bay .
You have been looking in the wrong place , my son .
MAN : Here it is .
Thank you .
RUTHVEN : He told me we must find a shrine .
An ancient myth said it had healing powers .
It was on an empty island off a barren coast .
I thought it the desperate quest of a dying man .
It was a sinister black thumbnail
sticking out of the ocean ,
more rock than island .
( SQUEAKING )
The oarsmen wouldn 't set foot on the place .
Said it was cursed .
The way was steep , but Darvell kept on climbing regardless .
I thought , or maybe I hoped ,
his heart would give way .
( DARVELL COUGHS )
Is this what you 've dragged us here to find ?
A hermit 's hut ?
RUTHVEN : I hated that place .
There were so many birds in the sky , almost darkened the sun .
They seemed to know something we didn 't .
He sent me to fetch water .
That was just a ruse .
Ahh .
Ahh !
( SQUEAKING )
I found the corpse .
His breath had gone .
His soul had fled .
And I ran .
I 've never spoken of it since .
I took his rings .
Ahoy !
And when I returned , I took his property .
Everything I own is his .
What will he do ?
( TV PLAYS DRAMATIC MUSIC )
( PANTS )
Bear in mind , Mr Kent ,
this woman is not your sister-in-law .
She 's dead . This is a shell .
And what it contains is pure evil .
- ( BOTH GIGGLE ) - Oi ! Shh !
When we destroy it , we destroy only the evil .
( WOMAN SNARLS AND HISSES )
( DOORBELL RINGS )
- I 'll go . - No , no , no , no .
I 'll get it .
( WOMAN ON TV SCREAMS )
( LAUGHS ) Aren 't you a little young ?
Eleanor , is she in ?
Why ? What 's it to you ?
I read her story . Can you tell her , please ?
She 's not in .
Go on .
Off you go .
( CLIMACTIC MUSIC )
Ella .
Look , I understand what Claire 's had to do , right ,
'cause there 's money to be made , but ...
If you don 't like what Clara 's doing , tell her .
You don 't like it either . Do you , hey ?
Why 's she like that ? Why 's she so ...
What happened to her , Ella ?
- She got bitten by a vampire . - Did I ?
There was a boy for you at the door .
I sent him on his way .
He says he 's read your story .
- What story , Ella ? - The one we always tell .
About the care home and how my sister rescued me .
It 's homework .
You frighten me sometimes .
Don 't .
I won 't .
Fucking brilliant story .
Thank you .
But the assignment asked for truth .
I didn 't write it as an assignment .
I wrote it for you .
I don 't want to lie anymore .
Something has to change .
But this ...
It 's crazy .
I thought
if I told
all the walls would come tumbling down .
Yes .
I think ... I get that you 're using the story
to say that bad things happened .
But ... why don 't you just say the truth ?
I am Eleanor Webb .
I 've given you my secret .
I 've told you how I live .
( ' CLAIR DE LUNE' BY CLAUDE DEBUSSY PLAYS )
Hello .
Would you put the record on ?
( WOMAN SINGS FRANZ SCHUBERT LIED )
It 's called ' Nacht und Traume ' .
ELEANOR : Peace be with you .
May light shine upon you .
( PLAYS SIMPLE CHORD PROGRESSION )
I think you should read this .
( CONTINUES PLAYING )
I set this every year . It 's this simple autobiography .
And then I get this amazing piece .
It 's as if Edgar Allan Poe and Mary Shelley
had got together and had a very strange little child .
( READS ) " A true account of my making
" and my life and death from the year of my birth , 1804 . "
You 're kidding . ( CHUCKLES )
If that was a piece of fiction , you 'd say it was ... it was
dark , passionate , violent , sick , brilliant bit of writing .
But she 's saying , " This is who I am . "
Which makes me think there 's something going on with her .
She 's a very closed-off kid .
Well , she wants to communicate , obviously .
I mean , look at the effort she 's made .
Her handwriting . Turn of phrase .
I mean , who writes like this these days ?
" As darkness fell ,
" the soucriant returned . "
ELEANOR : And Captain Ruthven prepared for the worst .
I took these for safekeeping .
Forgive me , my friend .
Forgiveness is a Christian value , Ruthven .
My gods are older .
More ruthless .
You died .
How else does one find life eternal ?
I sent you to fetch water .
And I met the nameless saint .
( SQUEAKING )
Ahh !
This is what happens .
When ?
When you pray for it .
( SCREAMS )
DARVELL : I rose and saw with different eyes .
Everything I looked on was a source of wonder .
But my vision had a price .
My soul was lost .
The price of my existence is this sacrifice .
- ( COUGHS ) - It flows from ...
DARVELL : It flows from blood .
His blood is yours .
Drink , my son .
( MUFFLED SCREAM )
DARVELL : Mine is a cruel existence .
But you do have the qualities one needs .
You are ever
a survivor .
I would give my soul to be as you are now .
So be it .
DARVELL : Eternal life
will only come to those prepared to die .
- Hello . - You want up ?
Thanks .
Have some fun now .
Hello ?
- Mr Minton . - Hello , Noel .
How are you ?
What , have I got a detention or something ?
No .
I 'm actually trying to get some information
on one of our current students , Eleanor Webb ?
- She gave this as her address . - Eleanor ? ls everything OK ?
We 're trying to set up a meeting
with all the parties interested in her welfare .
Sure .
Are her parents here ?
Um ...
No , you need to speak to Claire .
She 's Eleanor 's big sister . Claire 's her legal guardian .
- Is Claire here ? - No , she 's , um ...
- ( GROUP LAUGHS ) - " busy .
It 's not what you think .
It 's Claire 's business , right ?
She saves girls from the streets .
The thing is , Noel , Eleanor 's written a story .
And in her story , she says that she lives with vampires .
So can you please pass this letter on
and tell Claire that if I don 't hear from her today ,
then I 'll be in touch with Social Services
and the police .
Shit .
So Darvell gave the map and passage to your mother ?
No , to Captain Ruthven .
ELEANOR : My mother saw her chance and took it .
- Arrgh ! - ( GRUNTS )
Arrgh ! Bitch !
Bitch ! Bitch !
ELEANOR : She stole the map and rode into the night
towards her unknown future .
WOMAN : And she made her way to where ? To this ruin ?
And this ' soucriant ' thing took her ?
I didn 't give you my story . I 've been betrayed into this .
You can leave any time you like .
So when did Clara come back for you ?
When I was 16 .
And what did she do in the meantime ?
- She 's never talked about it . - Really ?
She says she can 't recall , but I expect she 's lying .
Lying is a way of life to her .
But I was raised in an orphanage
where I was taught to tell the truth .
Are there others like you ?
I 've never met one .
And Clara never speaks of any .
I think we 're the only two who still endure .
- How often do you feed ? - I 'd rather not talk about it .
- Ah . - Thank you .
That 's the distasteful part of being an immortal , isn 't it ?
If you don 't believe a word I say , why this pretence ?
Eleanor .
How can you be two centuries old ?
By ... by what miracle of science ?
You see
that 's the tricky thing .
Because it 's only over time that I can prove it .
30 , maybe 40 years from now ,
when you 're pruning roses from your wheelchair
I 'll stroll by your garden gate
and say , " Hello , Morag . "
And nothing will have changed .
I am 16 forever .
And you 'll realise this ,
and it will hurt your heart ,
and I 'll say , " May peace be with you . "
And I 'll help you with the pain .
Why don 't you do it now ?
I 'm not strong . You could overpower me .
You 're not ready .
( PLAYS SHOSTAKOVICH 'S ' PRELUDES AND FUGUES Op. 87 , No. 2 IN A MINOR ' )
How do you do it ?
( STOPS PLAYING )
Where are your fangs ?
Why don 't you die in the daylight ?
How could you give my story to those people ?
- I wrote it for you . - How do you kill ?
I never .
People have to consent .
They have to want .
Want death ?
- It has to be an act of ... - Who the fuck wants death ?
Sometimes it releases people .
- So you 're moral ? - No .
- I 'm ruthless . - Bullshit .
All this , " I 'm 206 , I remember everything , and it 's a burden . "
It 's pathetic .
( SIGHS )
My mum 's giving me a birthday party .
It 's not really a party 'cause I 'm only inviting you .
- Will you come ? - Yes .
Good .
( RESUMES PLAYING SHOSTAKOVICH 'S 'PRELUDES AND FUGUES ' )
( RINGS DOORBELL )
( BREATHES DEEPLY )
Hi .
Happy birthday .
For you .
Do I have to invite you in ?
You 'd better come in .
GABI : Hello again , Eleanor .
ELEANOR : Hello .
Seriously , you can try if you like .
I was hoping to arrange a more official meeting ,
Ideally with the school counsellor
and with Eleanor herself .
Well , what 's the problem ?
'Cause , you know , usually she sails through school .
Well , Eleanor wrote her life story
and she 's quite insistent that it 's true .
I don 't expect you to be flattered by this ,
but in it , she describes you as a soucriant ,
which I believe is a sort of vampire .
( LAUGHS ) Well !
She has got a great imagination .
I hope she gets top marks . Who else has read it ?
You have sole care of her , don 't you ?
That boy , Frank . I bet he 's read it .
Quite a responsibility for somebody so young .
I 'm doing just fine , thank you .
So , I shoot the bastard Ruthven
and I nick the map , and then what ?
Well , it ends . She doesn 't say , does she ?
That 's ' cause I never told her .
Shall we arrange a more formal meeting ?
I saw that Ruthven wasn 't dead . I should have killed him then .
But I had mercy on the cunt .
Now , hold that thought , because I 'll tell you what he did .
But first , shall I tell you what it was like for me ?
OK .
It was wonderful .
I had eyes that cut through lies ,
lungs that breathed eternity .
I felt I 'd lived my whole wretched life
just to prepare me for that moment .
( STIRRING CHORAL MUSIC )
- Ahh !
( GROWLS )
It was easy .
( GASPS )
Where 's Ruthven ?
He wasn 't worthy of your gift .
You stole it ?
Are we thieves now ?
Do we steal time ?
We buy it .
With blood .
We are a brotherhood .
There are no women amongst us .
MAN : What is her parentage ?
- It is low . - And her life before ?
- She made ends meet ... - I was a harlot .
But that is in the past .
Some things are eternal .
You were to find a man of good blood
who appreciates this brotherhood and what we do .
What is it you do ?
We are the pointed nails of justice .
How will you use this gift ?
To punish those who prey on the weak ,
to curb the power of men .
We should not permit her to survive .
MAN : We have no choice .
Unless she breaks our code .
You have no part in our order .
MAN 2 : Truly , you 're base .
Will you not speak for me ?
CLARA : They banished me .
I learnt that immortality is unendurable alone .
So I came back .
I watched my daughter grow .
She was my only link with everything alive .
WOMAN : Back to sleep .
Back to sleep .
You .
Come on .
( GASPS )
It was because of Eleanor I broke their code .
How did you do that ?
A woman 's not permitted to create .
I took my darling to the nameless isle
and I let the thing save her .
And for that , they would annihilate us both .
You see , I had made a fatal error .
- ( GASPS ) - I 'd been merciful .
I 'd let Ruthven live .
( CLARA SCREAMS ) Eleanor !
Eleanor !
Give my regards to your mother .
And welcome to a slow death .
Eleanor !
Welcome , whore .
No ! ( SCREAMS )
Die ! Die !
Now you know everything .
I 'm never merciful .
And knowledge is a fatal thing .
- ( GRUNTS ) - Ahh .
ELEANOR : When I was born , there were only seven planets .
Neptune hadn 't been discovered , so nobody believed in it .
Heaven and earth are full of things we don 't yet understand .
I had a year of chemotherapy .
Which was too much time lying in my bed .
So
I made this .
That 's you .
Near the sun .
Where it 's warm and bright .
And that 's me .
Where light barely penetrates .
And it 's cold .
And time moves so slowly .
You 're not cold .
Everything outside of time is cold .
If you kiss me right now
will I live forever ?
( GASPS )
I 'm sorry .
Wait !
Stop !
Why do you always run away from me ?
If you stay with me , you 'll die .
I 'm dying anyway -
It isn 't life I offer you . Do you understand that ?
You 'll take life .
By consent , like you do .
It 's still monstrous .
You 'll leave everything behind .
Except you .
Come here .
The gift I gave you , open it .
Wait until I knock .
MORAG : Kevin ?
Do you want to come to ...
There you are . I 've been worried sick .
Look . Claire 's not happy .
I 've made changes , sent the girls home ,
Bought ' em tickets on the Eurostar .
It 's gonna be a clean house now .
- Noel , I 'm leaving . - What are you talking about ?
What do you think you 're doing ,
telling that fucking school who we are ?
I hate the way you speak . It makes me sick !
How dare you put us in such danger ?
You told that fucking teacher our story !
I listened to his crap about your fantasies of death ,
and all the while , he was implying my neglect .
- Neglect , Eleanor , of you ! - Stop it , Claire !
There is a rule that we live by ! And you broke it !
- What if I broke free ? - No !
To tell another is forbidden .
Those with knowledge have to die .
You made that rule so you could isolate me .
No , I 've kept you safe !
You stupid fucking cunt , Mother ! I hate you !
( SOBS )
- No , no , no , no , no ! Leave her ! - Ella ! Get off me !
- Come back , Ella ! Ella ! - Can 't you leave her alone ?
- Just ... - Eleanor !
- Claire ! - No , you can 't leave !
- You 're making it worse ! - It 's not safe , Eleanor !
You can 't leave !
- ( GRUNTS ) - Claire , just leave her be !
( GRUNTS )
- No ! - ELEANOR : Clara ?
- You can 't leave ! It 's not safe ! - Clara .
She has every right to go ! ( SCREAMS )
- No ! - ( THUD )
( GASPS )
- Know where she lives ? - MORAG : Yes .
I believe it 's a hotel on the seafront .
- Does she trust you ? - Maybe .
- I 've never lied to her . - That 's good .
What will happen ?
She 'll be taken somewhere safe .
We just want to talk to her .
You 've told your little boyfriend
- all about us , haven 't you ? - No !
You know what happens to those with knowledge , Ella !
- No , Clara , don 't ! - It 's like a virus .
It 's deadly , needs to be stamped out .
- Clara , please , don 't ! - I know where he lives !
Don 't ! Clara , don 't go !
Clara ! Clara !
( GRUNTS )
- ( MOBILE PHONE BUZZES ) - ( GASPS )
Hello
Frank .
Where 's Eleanor ?
She 's got a message for you . Can I come in ?
Well , you 're gonna have to come out here , then , aren 't you ?
( PANTS )
I must say , you are definitely Ella 's type .
Earnest , clueless , about as sexy as a pair of shoes .
I knew you wouldn 't let her go without a fight .
Oh . Is that what you 're suggesting , Frank ?
A fight ?
Go on . Finish me .
I still have the advantage .
She 's going to leave you anyway .
( MOBILE PHONE RINGS )
ELEANOR ON PHONE : Frank , Clara 's coming .
Don 't answer the door . Don 't let her in .
I 'm trapped here . She caught me .
Just don 't let her get you .
It 's too late , my love .
I will never forgive .
I will never , ever forgive !
Eleanor ! What the hell is going on ?
It 's Clara . You have to stop her .
These men are looking for her . Where is she ?
- She 's here . - Ella .
Eleanor , you have to tell us the truth .
Something terrible has happened to Kevin .
- Clara Webb ? - Who is this ?
You know who we are , whore mother .
I will take care of Eleanor now .
Ella ! Ella !
( GRUNTS )
These men are from the police , Eleanor . They 've come to help .
- We have to get to Frank . - We will get to Frank .
We need to get you to a doctor , Eleanor . Don 't run !
What are you doing ? We need to get to Frank .
You don 't need handcuffs ! She 's a child .
- Eleanor , I 'm coming with you . - Be calm .
( PANTS )
I will be with you whatever happens .
There 's no need to be afraid .
Of course not .
It 's a privilege to meet you , Eleanor .
I thought Clara and I were the only ones .
Surely she told you of the brotherhood .
Excuse me ? What are you saying ?
Darvell . You 're just as I imagined .
Help me .
MORAG : Where exactly are you taking us ?
Because we 've just gone right past the police station
and the hospital .
Seriously , where are we going ?
- Eleanor ! - ( TYRES SCREECH )
Eleanor !
- Ella ! Ella ! - Mother !
They 'll destroy you , Ella ! They 'll destroy you !
Darvell , let her go ! ( SCREAMS )
Mother !
- Darvell , let her go ! - Mother !
Now I 'm going to show you , piece of whore .
- ( CLARA SCREAMS ) - Yes !
- ( TYRES SCREECH ) - Oh , my God , you killed her .
Nothing is that easy .
- ( WHIMPERS ) - Mother !
- Mother ! - With this act ,
- I cleanse the earth ! - ( GRUNTS )
- Mother ! - No !
- ( WHIMPERS ) - Be calm . Be calm .
Who are you people ?
- I said be calm ! - ( BONES CRACK )
I hate these crying women .
Damn you .
I 've followed you for many years .
You take only those who are ready .
And that has a certain grace .
You have been condemned from the moment Clara made you .
Our code does not permit women to create .
In her stories , you were wonderful .
You had compassion and respect .
You gave her life .
She stole her life .
Please . Please stop him .
She killed one of the brethren , and that 's unforgivable .
Don 't go .
Amazing how two little girls with no money and learning
slipped through your fingers for an eternity .
( SHOUTS AGGRESSIVELY )
( SCREAMS )
- Hold her down ! - Ella !
- Hold her down . - No ! No ! No !
( SCREAMS ) No !
No ! Ella !
Ella ! Ella !
Eleanor !
- Stop it ! - Bring it here .
Bring it here . Isn 't the present everything ?
Ella !
This is your last night , witch .
- Darvell ! - Last night !
Eleanor !
( BLADE SCRAPES )
This blade is from Byzantium . My souvenir of the Crusades .
May it send you to eternity .
It was on a beach like this that we first met .
But I went with Ruthven , for all my damnation .
But it was you .
You were the pearl .
See how the bitch uses her arts to the last ?
The honour is yours .
Do what you like with me , but let her go , please !
- Hold her still . - Please ! I beg you , Darvell !
- Still , I said . - She 's going to die anyway .
She can 't survive on her own .
- Eleanor ! - ( SCREAMS )
My baby !
( SQUELCH )
You truly are a wonder .
( BOTH SOB )
I 've been following you for years , so assiduously .
Because if I wasn 't the one to find you ,
they certainly would have killed you .
What will they do , the others ?
The brotherhood is strong .
Unchanging .
They will come .
With their pointed nails of justice .
Will he travel with us now ?
You 're not coming with us .
What ?
I 'm cutting you loose .
You can 't stay with your mother all your life , can you ?
Come on .
Come here .
( ELEANOR CRIES )
Go on .
Look forward , not back .
Always .
( SOBS )
Your instinct is to hunt the powerful and protect the weak .
I 'd like to try and live that way .
Live your life how you choose . It 's no concern of mine .
If you could have anything , what would it be ?
Your pardon .
In time . Maybe .
Your company , then ?
We have time .
FRANK : I 'm afraid .
ELEANOR : Don 't be .
ELEANOR : I am Eleanor Webb .
I throw my story to the wind , and never will I tell it more .
Another one begins .
( SQUEAKING )
( GENTLE MYSTERIOUS MUSIC )
( CHOIR SINGS ) ♪ Lully , lullay Thou little , tiny child
♪ Bye-bye , lully , lullay
♪ O sisters too How may we do
♪ For to preserve this day ?
♪ This poor youngling for whom we do sing
♪ Bye-bye , lully , lullay . ♪
( MYSTERIOUS MUSIC )